Finding Aid for the Donald Kalish Papers LSC.0578
UCLA Library Special Collections
Donald Kalish papers
1927-2000
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kalish, Donald, 1919-2000
LSC.0578
91.2 linear feet (228 boxes)
Donald Kalish, born December 4, 1919, was a logician, UCLA professor, and anti-war activist. His areas of expertise included logic and set theory. Kalish was known for his activism and opposition to the Vietnam War, as well as US military involvement in Central America and for hiring Angela Davis in 1969. This collection consists of materials related to Kalish's writings, teaching career, research, political activities, and personal life. The papers include course materials, lecture notes, correspondence, scrapbooks, political ephemera, newspaper clippings, photographs, and audio tapes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
This collection may contain sensitive materials, such as medical information, financial forms, or student grades. In order to access materials that are protected under HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act) or for which there is sensitive health information, please submit a research protocol to Library Special Collections at speccoll@library.ucla.edu.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio and audiovisual materials. Audio and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anna Kalish. Addition, 2000.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9950208773606533
Biography/History
Donald Kalish, born December 4, 1919, was a logician, UCLA professor, and anti-war activist. Born in Chicago, Kalish earned his bachelor's and master's degrees in psychology at UC Berkeley. He also received his doctorate in philosophy from UC Berkeley in the late 1940s. He later taught at Swarthmore College before moving to UCLA in 1949 and where he served as chairman of the UCLA Philosophy Department from 1964 to 1970. His areas of expertise included logic and set theory, and he worked closely with Richard Montague to develop formal logical proofs by natural deduction. Together they published Logic: Techniques of Formal Reasoning in 1964. Kalish later published a second edition in 1980 with Gary Mar.
Kalish was known for his activism and opposition to the Vietnam War, as well as US military involvement in Central America. He was also responsible for hiring to Angela Davis teach in the Philosophy Department in 1969 and continued to support her after UC Board of Regents attempted to dismiss her for her political views. His other activities include founding the Concerned Faculty of UCLA, membership in the University Committee on Vietnam, tax protests to avoid funding the war, and vice-chairman of the Peace Action Council, Los Angeles. Kalish led a 1967 Peace Action Council protest against President Lyndon Johnson's Vietnam policies at the Century Plaza Hotel in Los Angeles, which brought out 10,000 people. He was also an organizer for the 1967 March on the Pentagon. Kalish retired in 1997. He passed away on June 8, 2000, in Los Angeles at the age of 80.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials related to the writings, teaching career, research, political activities, and personal life of UCLA Philosophy Professor Donald Kalish. The papers include course materials, lecture notes, correspondence, scrapbooks, political ephemera, newspaper clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, photographs, and audiovisual materials. Issues addressed in this collection include Angela Davis' hiring, Vietnam War protests, taxpayers against the war, the trial of the Chicago Seven, opposition to US involvement in El Salvador and Central America, conscientious objectors, various student movements and civil rights concerns, including the Iranian Student Union. Additional materials include course materials from his time at Swarthmore College, correspondence with family members, and photographs from Kalish's college years.
Arrangement
This collection does not have series and has been arranged at the file level.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- California -- Los Angeles.; Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944-; Kalish, Donald, 1919-2000 -- Archives; University of California, Los Angeles. Department of Philosophy--Faculty -- Archives
- "Movement Actions and Requests" newsletters, fliers, and correspondence (Summer), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- National Association for Irish Justice, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Constitutional Convention: Panther Call," Black Panther newsletters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 2nd conspiracy pledge, 1970 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Guardian editorials by Sid Lens and Jerry Gordon, 1970 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Communists on Campus" TV show, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chicano Moratorium fliers and clippings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Peace Action Coalition posters and fliers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- W.B. Mason case, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- People's Coalition memo, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Strategy Action Anti-War Conference (Milwaukee, Wisconsin), 1970 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Fliers and correspondence for various movements, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Psycho surgery and Nixon, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- War in Vietnam conferences (Vancouver, Meacham, and Kaufmann), 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Appointments, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Anti-war protest scrapbook, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Committee of Concerned Faculty meeting minutes and essays, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Angela Davis and other issues at UCLA scrapbook, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Benjamin Spock indictment scrapbook, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- UCLA Vietnam teach-in: Student group announcements on Vietnam War Discussion Forum, 1965 October (Box 3, Folder 1)
- UCLA Vietnam teach-in: Speakers schedule, 1969 November (Box 3, Folder 2)
- UCLA Vietnam teach-in: Notes and correspondence for approval, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- University Committee on Vietnam: Thank notes, fliers and correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- University Committee on Vietnam: Correspondence with Donald Duncan and committees, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- University Committee on Vietnam: Fundraising for UCV, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Kalish comments and term paper on metaphysics, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "Selected Topics" by T.W. Stone, 1944 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Aristotle's syllogistic analysis and modern formal logic, Jan Jukasiewicz, 1952 February (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Notes on Leibniz, Arnauld correspondence, 1947 September-November (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Notes on Kalish, Russell, and Couturat's Leibniz reviews, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lecture notes on Aristotle 1-21, 1952 March-May (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lecture notes on Aristotle 22-29 (Metaphysics), 1952 March-May (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "Concerning Being and Essence" by St. Thomas Aquinas, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bibliographies and exams, 1944, 1948, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Lecture notes on Aristotle 39-42, posterior analytics, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Notes and lectures on ethics (36-38), 1948, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence with Kalish's father and brother, Bud, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Childhood correspondence with Bud, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Lecture notes on Aristotle (30-35), undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence with a naval officer, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Angela Davis' reappointment and Regents' arguments, 1970 June (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Committee of Liason correspondence with Congress, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Encyclopedia of Philosophy article correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Manuscript for Encyclopedia of Philosophy article, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Encyclopedia of Philosophy article final draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- John O. Stewart works and resume, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Bessie Jones, For the Ancestors," collected and edited by John O. Stewart, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Stickfighting: Ritual Violence in Trinidad" by John Stewart, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "Image and Power in the Trinidad Carnival," by John Stewart, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- KPFK's Paul Dallas issue, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Resist: Meeting minutes, essays, and newsletters, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Resist: Correspondence and fliers, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Resist: Address list, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Resist: Minutes and announcements, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Resist: Articles, fliers and correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Resist: Minutes, fliers and articles, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Valley State trial, Congress of American Philosophers, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Reports on ROTC and recruiting on campus, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Dr. Spock party and fundraising, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation anti-war bulletins, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Leave of absence and re-admission, Maizlish indictment, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- "Logic Techniques of Formal Reasoning," Kalish-Montague, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Notes on set theory, equivalent and CB theorem, 1973-1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Set theory notes, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Shutte, current and past work, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Proofs and derivations: Recursion schema, Zorn's lemma, and correlation theorems, 1991, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Lecture notes: "Given Behind Current Frong", 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Notes, data, office hours and other materials, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Thoughts for tests or lectures, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Various teaching materials, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Chapter 4 solutions for exercises and new problems, 1982-1984, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Chapter 4, section 6-9 solutions to exercises and new problems, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Weakened Shutte problem, second beginning, 1989 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with Muhammad Ali, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Wesley Robert Wells death penalty, 1947-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Playboy interview of William Sloane Coffin, 1968 August (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Ernst Straus on Lebanon invasion, 1982 June 23 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Interview of Kalish and Angela Davis in Christian Science Monitor, 1969 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with Los Angeles Times, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Campus as sanctuary for refugees, clipping and correspondence, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Stanley Scheinbaum forum correspondence, 1989 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Various pamphlets on civil rights, 1966, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Correspondence and articles regarding Fort Hood Three, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Set theory, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Concerned Faculty: Anti-Contra letters to Congress, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence to Congress on Gulf War and Iran-Contra Affair, 1986-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Concerned faculty materials, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Letters to Sidney Peck, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Letters to and from Malcolm Dundan, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Letters to John Dolan, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Wallace Thomas, "A Death Row Inmate", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Postcard from Marian Dobrosielski, 1960 July 22 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings on Angela Davis, 1969-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and articles on Angela Davis, 1969-1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Copies of The Militant newsletter, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Mr. Logic t-shirt, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook on Vietnam War, 1965 October-November (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Newspaper: County Iota Gazette, "Present Administration Seeks Reelection", 1935 April (Box 9, Folder 3)
- St. Louis Daily Globe, "Kampfer Pins Dusek in Arena Mat Feature Before Throng", 1931 September 17 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Diplomas, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Final notes (Spring), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Infinite model proofs and work, Kalish, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Lecture materials and take-home exam, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Class notes on infinite and finite models, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- NTT work, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Assigned exercises, Manuel Cabrera, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Final exam and make-up exam (Winter), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- A set of infinite model problems, 1996 July (Box 10, Folder 8)
- A discovery called "Fun", 1994 June (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Selected challenging problems, 1996 June-August (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Infinite Model problems, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Various Finite Model problems, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Philosophy 32: Lecture notes 12-20, 1996 March-May (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Philosophy 32: Final and answer key, 1996 March-May (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Personal correspondence while at Berkeley, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Personal correspondence while at Tuscon, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Family letters received before, 1932-1937 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Cards received before school, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Letters from camp and home, 1935-1939 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Personal correspondence received in St. Louis, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Family correspondence while at Berkeley, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Correspondence received at Camp Nebagamon, Wisconsin, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Correspondence received at Camp Nebagamon, Wisconsin, 1940 June-August (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Personal correspondence while at Berkeley, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Personal correspondence, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Old school report on Greek myths, 1934 December (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Set Theory: Copy in preparation, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Assorted proofs and table of contents, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Daily Bruin articles on Benjamin Spock indictment, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Daily Bruin on Angela Davis, 1969 September-November (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Daily Bruin on Angela Davis, 1969 September-November (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Anti-war literature, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Titles: Los Mangantes de Castilla, 25 Years After, Whither China, The Quotable, and The Tragic Gap.
- Anti-war literature, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Titles: The Fort Hood Three, 1001 Ways to Beat the Draft, High Tide of Black Resistance, and Drama Survey.
- Anti-war literature, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Titles: For a Meaningful Alternative, Case Study of a Riot, and clippings from St Louis Dispatch.
- Philosophy 32: Lecture notes for winter, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- AAUP Censure Report on Angela Davis and UC policy, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Angela Davis from Vice-Chancellor Saxon, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- AAUP news release and censure of UC Regents for banning Davis, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Letters of support for Angela Davis from philosophy departments, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Articles on Angela Davis, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- William Divale's disclosure on being an FBI informant in the Daily Bruin, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Various papers on Gulf War and correspondence with Congress, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Jennifer Casolo event clippings, articles, and fliers, 1990 January (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Dissertations of John Stewart, 1976-1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Sidney Peck sexual harassment charges, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Sidney Peck, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Retirement announcement to Joyce Appleby, 1999 July 19 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Low turn-out for anti-war teach-in articles, 1967 October (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Vietnam vigil poster and article, 1972 October (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Article on Kalish's refusing support income tax for war, 1967 March (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Articles on Kalish filing suit against IRS, 1969, 1991-1992. (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Caricatures of Donald Kalish, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Concerned Faculty at UCLA correspondence, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Articles on anti-war activism, 1981-1984 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Concerned Faculty: Meeting minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Concerned Faculty: Agendas, meeting materials, and membership forms, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Vietnam teach-in organization work, 1965 November (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Vietnam Committee expenses and contracts with speakers, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Correspondence to Congress from University Committee on Vietnam (UCV), 1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- UCV activities: Work lists and contact info, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
- UCV programs and finances, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- UCV party guest lists, 1967 August (Box 17, Folder 8)
- UCV meeting agendas, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- UCV repaid loans, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Jack Robinson issue, 1968 July (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Political cartoons on Vietnam, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Anti-war activities, 1970-1973 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Letters of interests, Angela Davis, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Students for a Democratic Society suspension and other correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- DC Nine and suit against Dow Chemical Company, newsletter, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Bar Sinister, Anderson and Lund correspondence and newsletters, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Firearms and self-defense handbook, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Correspondence to and from activist organizations and coordinators, 1967 June (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Correspondence with Benson Mates on Vietnam, 1967 May (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Business and activism correspondence, 1967 May (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Bertrand Russell obituary photographs and clippings, 1962 June (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with Senators Alan Cranston, James Abourezk, and George Brown Jr. on Vietnam, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Correspondence on conference planning on Vietnam, 1967-1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Reviews of Kalish's book and articles on his teach-ins, 1967, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with John Stewart, 1975 February 5 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Howard Zinn, 1969 January 17 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- The Southern Comfort party book, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Rosella Johnson incident, credit card fraud, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with probation officer for Robert Lee appeal, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Class of 1969 15-year reunion invitation, 1984 September 21 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Vietnam Day materials, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Personal and academic notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Memorabilia (Jack Palevsky and Montague's funeral), undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Career-related materials, 1950, 1986, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Reel 1, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: Gugat (12:55-1:17). Simon Cassidy (1:30-1:55). Side2: Bertrand Russel (6:38-6:45). Sheinbaum. Slight damage to tape.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
- Reel 2, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: Blecthreu (5:20-5:22) Stanton and Kirby (5:22-5:55). Side 2: Millett (10:40-11:20) Panel. Slight damage to tape.
- Reel 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: Scheer (4:04-4:30). Side 2 Questions for Scheer (4:35-5:17). Slight damage to tape.
- Reel 4, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: Gorny (12:20-12:25) Panel (12:25-2:55). Side 2: Sweezy (6:00-6:37).
- Reel 5, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: Saddi Chawla(2:00-2:20) George Brown(2:30-2:45). Side 2: McReynolds(10:00-10:03) Mark Mancal. Slight damage to tape.
- Reel 6, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  1/4 inch open reel audio. Side 1: 7:30-8:20, Side 2: 8:20-9:10, Panel: Benwick, Rolph, Scheer, Wilkinson, Windmiller. Slight damage to tape.
- Turning Point in China Book by William Hilton, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Spring Philosophy 134 grading materials, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Home remodeling papers (Project Overdrive), 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Philosophy 32: Final and lecture notes (Spring), 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Chapter 6, Section 6, Exercise 19, and Theorems T405-T416, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Chapter 6, Section 7, Exercises 20-23, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Chapter 6, Section 8, Exercises 24-25, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Chapter 6, Section 8, Group II, and Solutions 26-41, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Philosophy M221A materials, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Chapter 7, Section 3, Exercises 9-20, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Chapter 7: Considered problems, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Chapter 7, Section 3, and Exercises 21-29, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Chapter 7, Section 4, and Exercises 30-34, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Chapter 7, Section 5, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Biconditional proof theorem, 1984, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Philosophy 31: Lecture notes 10-20, final, and answer key (Winter), 1997 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Philosophy 31: Knights and Knaves Problems by Allan Nelson and Gary Marr (Winter), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Philosophy 31: Notes and student evaluations (Winter), 1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Philosophy 31: Lecture notes (Winter), 1985 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Philosophy 31: Exams (Winter), 1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Philosophy 133: Syllabus (Spring), 1989 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Chapter 10 textbook revisions and additions, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Philosophy 134: Syllabus and textbook (Spring), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Philosophy 134: Set theory (Spring), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Philosophy 133: Set theory (Spring), 1989 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Philosophy 31: Exam and class materials (Winter), 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Videocassettes, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  VHS. Tape 1: Undergraduate Association of Philosophy at UCLA. Don Kalish lecture on history of Philosophy Department. Tape 2: Colloquium on history of Philosophy Department at UCLA.
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page
- Philosophy 134: Notes to self, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Philosophy 134: Lecture notes and proofs of finite sets, 1982-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Philosophy 134: Class handouts, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Philosophy 134: Gerald Smith, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Philosophy 134: Lecture notes (Fall), 1994 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Morning logic, Peano's arithmetic, and set theory (Fall), 1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Peano proofs (Fall), 1996 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Peano subtraction, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Peano predecessor, 1996 July 30 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Review, 1996 September (Box 21, Folder 10)
- New insight on double induction, 1996 October 28 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Philosophy 31: Lecture 1-18 (Fall), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Peano arithmetic, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Various proofs, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Philosophy 31: Homework and tests (Fall), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Philosophy 31: Grader notes (Fall), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Philosophy 31: Enrollment lists (Fall), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Philosophy 31: Homework records (Fall), 1997 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Philosophy 31: Exercises, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
- Logic: Techniques of Formal Reasoning, Chapters 1-3, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Philosophy 31: Lectures 1-9 (Winter), 1997 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with Kalish, 1943-1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)